West Hartford, CT. Elmwood Community Church records, 1867-2024. RG5531
Congregational Library & Archives
West Hartford, CT. Elmwood Community Church records, 1867-2024.
Congregational Library & Archives
Elmwood Community Church
Elmwood Union Chapel Association
Ladies Benevolent Sewing Society
RG5531
18.40 Cubic Feet (18 boxes, 3 flat files, 1 object)
The Elmwood Community Church was founded in 1921 from the Elmwood Union Chapel Association with James F. English as its first pastor. Due to the growth of the church, the Sunday school, the Ladies Aid Society, and other organizations, a new church building was construction beginning in 1926 with a parsonage following in 1947. In 1958, the church steeple was raised. After 1967, the church continued to grow and change with the reorganization of boards and groups, renovation to the building, changing of pastors, and opening the facilities to the community. In 2024, the Elmwood Community Church permanently closed due to declining membership and funds. This collection includes records documenting the history, activities, and members of the church, Sunday school, and women's groups with minutes, building records, financial and legal records, newspaper articles, newsletters, reports, correspondence, programs, church histories, member records, and audio/visual materials.
Restrictions on access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by Elmwood Community Church in September 2024; 2024-39.
Historical Note
The Elmwood Community Church was founded in 1921 out of the Elmwood Union Chapel Association which was founded in 1897. The church began with 188 charter members representing 14 denominations and called James F. English as its first pastor. At the time the Sunday School and Ladies Aid Society were already established with the Sunday school being founded in 1873 and the Ladies Aid Society dating back to at least 1917 with the Ladies Benevolent Sewing Society going back further to 1857. Due to the growing membership in the church, Sunday school, ladies' society, and other organizations, the chapel building was quickly outgrown with construction for a new church beginning in 1926 along with the arrival of a new pastor, Charles K. Tracy, and the cornerstone laid in 1927. In 1947, the Cambridge St parsonage was constructed with the first occupant in 1948. In 1955, the church sanctuary was renovated along with the parish house in 1957. Shortly after in 1958, the church steeple was raised.
Between 1967 and 1969, the church experienced many changes with the disbanding of the women's federation that formed in 1928 from the Ladies Aid Society, the reorganization of the church boards, the burning of the mortgage, and the availability of church facilities to Greater Hartford organizations. Over the following years, the church formed and dissolved committees, updated the building and facilities, changed pastors, celebrated anniversaries, worked with the community, and opened their space to other community organizations and businesses. As the church entered the later 2010s and 2020s, membership and finances declined until the church permanently closed in 2024.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records documenting the history, activities, and members of the Elmwood Community Church in West Hartford, CT along with the associated Sunday school and women's groups of Elmwood. The collection contains documents, photographs, photo slides, VHS tapes, CDs, an audio reel, ledgers, notebooks, member cards, building plans, and photostat copies. The records include meeting minutes, financial records, legal records, newsletters, service and play programs, pamphlets, vital statistics, attendance and guest books, histories, newspaper articles, annual reports, correspondence, flyers and announcements.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series, five of which are furthered arranged into subseries. Records within the series and subseries have been arranged chronologically by start date except for series 2: Member records, 1916-2023 which is arranged alphabetically.
Series 1: Sunday School, 1867-2005
Series 2: Member records, 1916-2023
Series 3: Women's federation, 1871-2019
Subseries 1: Ladies sewing society, 1871-1918
Subseries 2: Ladies aid society, 1914-1936
Subseries 3: Circle 1, 1937-1961
Subseries 4: Circle 3, 1938-1972
Subseries 5: Circle 4, 1930-1990
Subseries 6: Circle 6, 1962-2019
Series 4: AV materials, 1921-2020
Subseries 1: Photos, 1921-2020
Series 5: Church boards, 1921-2024
Subseries 1: Board of missions, 1989-2019
Subseries 2: Christian education, 1975-2020
Subseries 3: Council, 1924-2024
Subseries 4: Deacons, 1936-2022
Subseries 5: Elmweds, 1948-1967
Subseries 6: Men's club, 1955-1982
Subseries 7: Trustees, 1927-2024
Series 6: Administrative recods, 1875-2023
Subseries 1: Annual Reports, 1921-2023
Subseries 2: Committees, 1949-2010
Subseries 3: Memorial funds, 1940-2022
Series 7: Church history, 1875-2024
Subseries 1: Member profiles, 1921-2021
Subseries 2: Newsletters, 1921-2023
Series 8: Yearly miscellaneous records, 1921-1995
Technical Requirements
Various hardware and software may be required to view the audio/visual materials and digital files included in the collection.
Related Materials
Additional records related Elmwood Chapel Association and Elmwood Community Church prior to 1952 can be found at the Conneticut State Library, and at FamilySearch.
Content Warning
This collection includes content and language that may be upsetting or triggering. These records reflect the language and attitudes of the historical period in which they were created; many of these terms are unacceptable today. The Congregational Library & Archives works to preserve Congregational history and stories while acknowledging that sometimes that history is problematic or questionable. We do this to preserve, contextualize, and reflect on the past so that we may learn from it.
This collection includes racist language and images.
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.).; Church records and registers.; Church membership.; Sunday schools.; Women -- Religious life.; Photographs.; Church architecture -- Designs and plans.; Programs; Church newsletters.; Church societies.; Church finance.; Elmwood Community Church; Elmwood Union Chapel Association; Ladies Benevolent Sewing Society; English, James F. (James Fairfield), 1896-1976
- Sunday school, 1867-2005
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records from the Elmwood Sunday school and nursery school including attendance books, minutes, reports, account books, and flyers.
  - Sunday School Ledger, 1867-1879 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sunday School Minutes and Account Book, 1873-1884 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1874-1875 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1876-1877 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1878-1879 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 18881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sunday School Attendance, 1886-1887 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sunday School Attendance and Minutes, 1889-1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sunday School Attendance, 1893-1899 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sunday School Annual Meeting Minutes, 1895-1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School Attendance, 1899-1903 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sunday School Attendance, 1903-1907 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sunday School Attendance Reports, 1904-1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sunday School Annual Reports, 1908-1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sunday School Attendance, 1912-1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sunday School Miscellaneous, 1913-2005 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sunday School Account Book, 1922-1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sunday School Attendance Book, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Church School Account Book, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Church School Payment Ledger, 1947-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sunday School Envelope Lists, 1949-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Nursery School, 1957-2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Sunday School Attendance Cards, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Sunday School Permanent Record Cards, 1950-1973 (Box 2)
- Member records, 1916-2023
  This series contains records and vital statistics relating to the members of Elmwood Community Church including member cards, member lists, guest books, baptismal records, member transfers, wedding announcements and information, funeral records, obituaries, directories, and registrar records.
  - 75th Anniversary Guest Book, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baptisms, 1989-2022 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bicentennial Guest Book, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Directories, 1977-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Directories, 2004-2022 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Funeral Clergy Records, 1983-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Funeral Services, 1936-2022 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Guest Book, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mailing Lists, 1944-1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Member Cards, 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Member Information, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Member Lists, 1944-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Member Statistics, 1921-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Membership Transfers, 1921-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Membership Transfers, 1990-2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Membership Transfers "A", 1933-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Membership Transfers "B", 1923-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Membership Transfers "C", 1930-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Membership Transfers "D", 1930-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Membership Transfers "E", 1922-1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Membership Transfers "F", 1932-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Membership Transfers "G", 1927-1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Membership Transfers "H", 1926-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Membership Transfers "I", 1976-1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Membership Transfers "J", 1929-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Membership Transfers "K", 1923-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Membership Transfers "L", 1929-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Membership Transfers "M", 1921-1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Membership Transfers "N", 1927-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Membership Transfers "O", 1925-1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Membership Transfers "P", 1924-1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Membership Transfers "R", 1924-1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Membership Transfers "S", 1927-1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Membership Transfers "T", 1922-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership Transfers "U" and "V", 1932-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership Transfers "W", 1926-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Transfers "Y" and "Z", 1942-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - New Member Announcements, 1997-2016 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - New Member Profiles, 1999-2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Obituaries, 1942-2013 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries, 1916-2023 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Officer List, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Parish List, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Photo Directories, 1969-2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Register, 1921-2016 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Registrar Book, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Registrar Book, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Registrar's Reports, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Weddings, 1987-2016 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Wedding Forms and Readings, 1993-2007 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Charter Members, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Guest Book, 1942-1952 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Guest Book, 1952-1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Guest Book, 1958-1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Guest Book, 1967-1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Guest Book, 1971-1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Guest Book, 1977-1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Guest Book, 1983-1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Wedding Announcements, 1947-2013 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries, 1908-2016 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Marriage, Funeral, and Transfer Cards, 1921-1996 (Box 17, Box 1)
  - Membership Cards, 1921-1950 (Box 17, Box 2)
  - Membership Cards, 1950-1973 (Box 17, Box 3)
  - Active and Inactive Cards, 1921-2016 (Box 18, Box 1)
  - Inactive and Alphabetical Baptism Cards, 1921-2010 (Box 18, Box 2)
  - Alphabetical and Chronological Baptism Cards, 1921-1991 (Box 18, Box 3)
  - Chronological and Numerical Baptism Cards, 1921-1995 (Box 18, Box 4)
  - Numerical Baptism Cards, 1947-1994 (Box 18, Box 5)
  - Marriage and Funeral Cards, 1926-1991 (Box 18, Box 6)
- Women's federation, 1871-2019
  This series contains records from the women's federation which grew from the ladies sewing society and ladies aid society in 1931 to include all the women in the church split between various circles and which disbanded in 1967 with the individual circles continuing separately. The series includes minutes, account books, reports, correspondence, and other documents relating to the various women's groups.
  - Ladies sewing society, 1867-1918
    This subseries contains records relating to the ladies benevolent sewing society in the south district of west hartford which began in 1857. The records include annual reports in two ledgers.
    - Ladies Sewing Society Annual Reports, 1871-1898 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Ladies Sewing Society Annual Reports, 1899-1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Ladies aid society, 1914-1936
    This subseries contains records including annual reports, minutes, and account books from the ladies aid society which became circle 1 of the women's federation in 1930.
    - Ladies Aid Society Cash Book, 1914-1922 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Ladies Aid Society Minutes, 1917-1924 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Ladies Aid Society Annual Reports, 1920-1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Ladies Aid Society Minutes, 1924-1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Ladies Aid Society Miscellaneous, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ladies Aid Society Minutes, 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Ladies Aid Circle Minutes, 1932-1936 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Circle 1, 1937-1961
    This subseries contains records from circle 1 of the women's federation which began as the ladies aid society and included annual reports and minutes.
    - Circle 1 Annual Reports and Minutes, 1949-1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Circle 1 Minutes, 1937-1944 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Circle 3, 1938-1972
    This subseries contains records including minutes and associated documents from circle 3 of the women's federation which merged with circle 5 in 1967 to become the daytime fellowship.
    - Circle 3 Minutes, 1938-1946 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Circle 3 Minutes, 1945-1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Circle 3 and Daytime Fellowship Minutes, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Circle 3 Minutes, 1967-1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Circle 4, 1930-1990
    This subseries contains records from circle 4 of the women's federation including minutes, account books, and related documents.
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1930-1935 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1937-1940 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1939-1947 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Circle 4 Miscellaneous, 1940-1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1952-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1970-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Circle 4 Minutes, 1976-1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Circle 4 Account Book, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Circle 6, 1962-2019
    This subseries contains records from circle 6 of the women's federation which disbanded in 2019 including minutes, member lists, and related documents.
    - Circle 6 Miscellaneous, 1962-2019 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Circle 6 Minutes, 1968-1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Circle 6 Minutes, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Circle 6 Minutes, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Women's Federation Miscellaneous, 1923-1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Women's Federation Minutes, 1931-1950 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Women's Federation Treasurer's Report, 1932-1949 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Women's Federation Financial Reports, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Women's Federation Account Book, 1933-1956 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Women's Federation Account Book, 1933-1960 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Women's Federation Executive Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Women's Federation Reports, 1941-1949 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Women's Federation Minutes, 1950-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Women's Federation Execxutive Reports, 1950-1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Women's Federation Treasurer's Reports, 1950-1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Women's Federation Reports, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Women's Federation Check Book, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Women's Federation Account Book, 1956-1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Women's Federation Check Book, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Women's Federation Check Book, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Women's Federation Reports, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Women's Federation Check Book, 1961-1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Women's Federation Executive Meetings, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Women's Federation Minutes, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Women's Federation Officer Installation, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- AV materials, 1921-2020
  This series contains audio/visual materials including CDs, VHS tapes, an audio reel, photographs, photo slides, photo negatives, reverend portraits, and digital photos.
  - Photos, 1921-2020
    This subseries contains photographs, photo slides, and photo negatives of church members, activities, and the building.
    - Brethren Service Center, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Polaroids, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Sunday School Rally Day, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Photos from tri-fold boards, 1921-1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Church Building, 1927-2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Wedding Photos, 1928-1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Photos, 1928-2006 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Photos, 1928-2011 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Rally Day, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Shows, 1941-1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Circle 4, 1943-1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Confirmation Class, 1950-1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Photo Slides, 1953-1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - West Hartford Centennial Exhibit, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - West Hartford Centennial Exhibit Negatives, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Sterling White, 1955-1958 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Steeple Raising, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Nursery School, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Directory Photo Collage, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - 50th Anniversary Dinner, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Ecumenical Service, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Anniversary Celebration, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Harvest Fair, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Reluctant Dragon Play, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Church Renovations, 1989-2010 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Bonnie Bardot Farewell, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Nick Davis, 1999-2007 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Ruth Porter, circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Steeple Painting, circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Memorial Garden Fountain Installation, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Korean Partnership, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - 85th Anniversary, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Lunch Brunch, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Quiet Room Dedication, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Photo Album, 2013-2014 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Reverend Portraits, 1921-2020 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Cornerstone and Call Bells, 1927-1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Photos and Descriptions, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Photos, 1927-1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Elmwood Com. Church May 2007 (Box 17, Item 1)
  - Susan Lyon Memorial Service, undated (Box 17, Item 2)
  - Oct 2008 Blessing of the Animals (Box 17, Item 3)
  - Choir Appreciation, 2008 (Box 17, Item 4)
  - ECC Outside Service Chicken BBQ, 2008 (Box 17, Item 4)
  - Sept 2008 Welcome Back Dinner (Box 17, Item 5)
  - Blessing of the Animals 10/11/2009 (Box 17, Item 6)
  - Children's Sunday, 2009 (Box 17, Item 7)
  - Choir Appreciation Strawberry Festival, 2009 (Box 17, Item 8)
  - May/June, 2009 (Box 17, Item 9)
  - ECC Pictures, 2010 (Box 17, Item 10)
  - ECC Pictures Christmas Pageant and Pancake Supper, 2010-2011 (Box 17, Item 11)
  - Jerry Gray, 2009 (Box 17, Item 12)
  - Organ Dedication, 1966 (Box 17, Item 13)
- Church boards, 1921-2024
  This series contains records from the church boards and organizations including minutes, financial records, correspondence, reports, and other related documents.
  - Board of missions, 1989-2019
    This subseries contains minutes and related documents from the board of missions.
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 2001-2008 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 2010-2015 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Board of Missions Minutes, 2016-2019 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Christian education, 1975-2020
    This subseries contains minutes and related documents from the christian education board.
    - Christian Education Minutes, 1975-1985 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Christian Education Minutes, 1986-1995 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Christian Education Minutes, 2001-2020 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Council, 1924-2024
    This subseries contains records from the church council which at times was known as the executive committee including minutes, reports, highlights, and related documents.
    - Executive Committee Micellaneous, 1924-1959 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Council Minutes and Correspondence, 1973-1985 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Council Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Council Minutes, 1977-1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Council Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Council Minutes, 1986-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Council Minutes, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Council Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Council Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Council Minutes, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Council Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Council Minutes, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Council Highlights, 1999-2005 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Council Minutes, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Council Minutes, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Council Minutes, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Council Minutes, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Council Minutes, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Council Minutes, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Council Minutes, 2008-2009 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Council Minutes, 2010-2012 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Council Minutes, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Council Moderator's Reports, 2014-2017 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Council Moderator's Reports, 2018-2021 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Council Minutes, 2020-2024 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Executive Committee Reports and Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Council Minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Council Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Council Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Deacons, 1936-2022
    This subseries contains records from the board of deacons which was at times known as the board of lay life and work. The records include minutes, reports, pamphlets, and other related documents.
    - Deacons' Minutes, 1936-1947 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Deacons' Minutes, 1948-1954 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Deacons' Minutes, 1954-1959 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Deacons' Minutes, 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 27)